RG 004:092, New Hartford Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
New Hartford Probate Court records
1834-1975
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (New Hartford District)
14.50 cubic feet
Record books, 1834-1973; Probate files, 1834-1975.
RG004_092
1912-005, 2011-088, 2011-089, T003304
Historical Note
New Hartford, Litchfield County, Town established in October 1738
The New Hartford Probate District was constituted May 27, 1825, from the Simsbury Probate District. The New Hartford Probate District included Barkamsted from May 1825 - June 4, 1834 and again from January 8, 2003 - January 4, 2011. The New Hartford Probate District merged with the Torrington and Winchester Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Torrington Area Probate District which serves the municipalities of Barkhamsted, Colebrook, Goshen, Hartland, New Hartford, Torrington, and Winchester.
Town of New Hartford, Probate District chronology:
October 1738 - January 1769, Hartford District
January 1769 - October 1808, Farmington District
October 1808 - May 26, 1825, Simsbury District
May 27, 1825 - January 4, 2011, New Hartford District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Torrington Area District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1834-1973. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 19. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1834-1975. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1834-1902 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered 3-19. One volume is 3B and 4 together. One volume is 3C.
Probate files in accession 1912-005 are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Wills in accession 2011-089 are arranged alphabetically within each box.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-005 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-089.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Barkhamsted; Probate records -- Connecticut -- New Hartford
Places:
Barkhamsted (Conn.); New Hartford (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1975 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15.
Accession 2011-088, Record books, 1827-1973, and Accession 2011-089, Probate files, 1879-1975, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-5, 7, 11, 1825-1930; probate files, 1834-1902; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-005 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): August 22, 1912 (1834-1902).
The record books in accession 2011-088 and probate files in accession 2011-089 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 21, 2010.
It is not known when the account book in accession T003304 was transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
Container List
- Record books, 1834-1973; 9 cubic feet (19 volumes); 2011-088
  - Records, 1834-1851 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1837-1853 (Volume 3B & 4)
  - Records, 1852-1853 (Volume 3C)
  - Records, 1866-1877 (Volume 5)
  - Decrees, 1875-1887 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1880-1891 (Volume 7)
  - Bonds, 1881-1936 (Volume 8)
  - Decrees, 1885-1893 (Volume 9)
  - Inventories, 1890-1924 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1886-1930 (Volume 11)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Administration Accounts, 1892-1924 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1891-1904 (Volume 13)
  - Decrees, 1893-1904 (Volume 14)
  - Orders & decrees, 1903-1913 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1904-1916 (Volume 16)
  - Orders & decrees, 1912-1925 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1916-1933 (Volume 18)
  - Inventories, 1916-1973 (Volume 19)
  - Miscellaneous - Account book for estate of Hiram Goodwin, 1885-1921
- Account book, 1877 - circa 1909; .25 cubic feet (1 volume); T003304
  - Estate of R. McD. Cleaveland, 1877 - circa 1909
- Probate files, 1834-1902; 3.25 cubic feet; 1912-005
  - Adams - Enright (Drawer 1)
  - Farley - MacNamera (Drawer 2)
  - MacNary - Smith (Drawer 3)
  - Spencer - Z (Drawer 4)
- Inventory Control Book, 1834-1902; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1912-005
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1879-1975; bulk 1910-1975; 2 cubic feet; 2011-089
  - Probate files (Drawer 1-2)